<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://origami.ft.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://origami.ft.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-06T17:41:03+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Origami Newsletter</title><subtitle>Origami is a group of services, components, and tools used to help design &amp; build digital products for FT brands.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, September 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/10/05/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, September 2021" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/10/05/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/10/05/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
TL;DR:
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; We made a monorepo, and gained a delivery manager&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-origami-component-system&quot;&gt;The Origami Component System&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing we’ve done this month is move all of our components into a single repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each component used to live in a separate code base, and that meant a lot of extra work when we want to make changes that affected more than one component. This work doesn’t change a lot by itself beyond how we work on components, but it is the foundation from which we’ll build a better component system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-this-affect-me&quot;&gt;How does this affect me?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How this change affects you depends on how you interact with Origami&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;origami-contributors&quot;&gt;Origami contributors&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to open an issue or a pull request on an Origami component, you should do it in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami&quot;&gt;Origami Component System repository&lt;/a&gt;. The testing in CI is so fast now, any change runs the test on every single component and for most changes it finishes in about 2 minutes. Everything else should be about the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation is a little light at the moment, but if you run into any trouble you can always talk to us in #origami-support or #origami-chat on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;origami-consumers&quot;&gt;Origami consumers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work itself doesn’t affect end-users of Origami, but later changes it unlocks (design tokens, better documentation, sass modules) will make your life better, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;designers&quot;&gt;Designers&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change won’t affect you yet, but the work we’re going to build on top of this will give you better insight into how a change to one component affects the others. And it’s the first step to Origami being the reference implementation of the design system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;everyone-else&quot;&gt;Everyone else&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sites that depend on Origami have a bright future of performing better and being more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;origami-has-a-new-team-member&quot;&gt;Origami has a new team member&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we last spoke, the team has grown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very happy to welcome aboard Kamran Muniree who is now serving as Origami’s delivery manager. He’s already made a big difference, and the team are very excited about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re also still hiring for an engineering role, so make sure you apply if you’ve ever wanted to work on Origami. There has never been a better time to be part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;origami-office-hours&quot;&gt;Origami Office Hours&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t new, but every week on a Friday at 2p.m. (London time) the team are available On-Line at a meeting called &lt;a href=&quot;https://calendar.google.com/event?action=TEMPLATE&amp;amp;tmeid=MWVzZDgzMmhtcXZhYTVvNmlyZXZyNm5tNjdfMjAyMTEwMDhUMTMwMDAwWiBjaGVlLnJhYmJpdHNAZnQuY29t&amp;amp;tmsrc=chee.rabbits%40ft.com&amp;amp;scp=ALL&quot;&gt;Origami Office Hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ever have any questions that you’d prefer talking through in person, you can pop by there and we’ll be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Kamran Muniree it is now available in the P&amp;amp;T calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;leaf rogers 🍃 for helping out Jake in an emergency when an unexpected large video found its way into the image service and ate all the memory and it crashed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/storybook/?path=/story/button--inverse&amp;amp;args=label:Edit;size:big;type:primary;icon:edit&quot;&gt;storybook config for o-buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added Origami website to monorepo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added script which logs out what releases will be made for which packages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replaced scroll event with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;IntersectionObserver&lt;/code&gt; to improve performance of o-layout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add wheat-100 to o-colors master brand palette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brought n-notification into the monorepo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;origami.json&lt;/code&gt; urls to point at the monorepo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added homepage, bugs and support email to the package.json of every component&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased the bottom margin of h2 and h3 editorial headings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>chee</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: We made a monorepo, and gained a delivery manager</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, July 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/08/09/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, July 2021" /><published>2021-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/08/09/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/08/09/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;
	TL;DR:
	&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; New introduction to Origami sessions and special thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a belated July update for you – it’s the holiday season! ☀️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re reaching the end of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;move from Bower to npm&lt;/a&gt;, a significant piece of work. Our focus now is on loose ends, bug fixes, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/07/01/origami-on-npm-and-how-to-migrate/&quot;&gt;supporting teams across the organisation through the migration guide&lt;/a&gt;. But we’re also working on proposals for our next big project(s) – focused on reducing technical complexity, increasing cross-group collaboration, and supporting new product development (super exciting, watch this space).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback or questions about the Bower to npm migration please let us know in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://financialtimes.slack.com/messages/origami-support&quot;&gt;#origami-support&lt;/a&gt; Slack channel or with an email to origami.support@ft.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-introduction-to-origami-sessions&quot;&gt;New Introduction To Origami Sessions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve scheduled new Introduction To Origami Sessions ✨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first session is useful for anyone who works in Product and Technology – we cover things at a high level rather than diving into too many technical details. Come along if you’d like to learn more about Origami projects, their goal, the team, and how to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami History&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second session explores components in more depth and includes technical details. It will be of particular interest to engineers and designers, although anyone is welcome:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Languages &amp;amp; Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Build Service / Manual Build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to hang back at the end to put some of what we learn into practice there will be an opportunity to run through a practical tutorial with some of the team on hand to answer any questions (optional)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be running the sessions Tuesday, 17th August from 10:30am (London time). Ask for an invite in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://financialtimes.slack.com/messages/origami-support&quot;&gt;#origami-support&lt;/a&gt; Slack channel or with an email to origami.support@ft.com. 🙌&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our special thanks this week goes to the Operations &amp;amp; Reliability team! The team have been working through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/07/01/origami-on-npm-and-how-to-migrate/&quot;&gt;Bower to NPM / Build Service v3 migration&lt;/a&gt; and have been very helpful by asking questions, raising any issues, and giving feedback along the way. Thanks for helping us improve the migration experience for other teams 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layers&quot;&gt;o-layers&lt;/a&gt; was not widely used and therefore did not meet its aim of managing the z-index between components and projects. There is no direct replacement for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-layers&lt;/code&gt;. Instead fire component specific events to indicate that a new “layer” such as an overlay has been opened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-navigation-data&quot;&gt;origami-navigation-data&lt;/a&gt; has been merged with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-navigation-service&quot;&gt;origami-navigation-service&lt;/a&gt; to reduce the complexity of our technical estate and speed up the release of changes to ft.com’s navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/scrumple&quot;&gt;scrumple&lt;/a&gt; was helpful when we needed to build bower components, but those days are now behind us. We recommend trying &lt;a href=&quot;https://esbuild.github.io/&quot;&gt;esbuild&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAJOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-footer&quot;&gt;o-footer&lt;/a&gt; introduces a new layout to support new Community &amp;amp; Events links (thanks for your work on this Ahmad Youssef and Max Bladen-Clark).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-autocomplete&quot;&gt;o-autocomplete&lt;/a&gt; has had a number of features enabled to support suggestions with more complex data structures and provide a callback function to action a users selection (thanks for the feedback and review Oliver Turner).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-table&quot;&gt;o-table&lt;/a&gt; based on feedback we’ve improved the demos and documentation for filterable tables; and we’ve added support for sorting tables with multiple header rows (thanks for raising and helping build a fix Emma Lewis).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;origami-build-service&lt;/a&gt; has received a number of bug fixes and improvements since the release of v3 last month, including an improved &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/url-updater&quot;&gt;“url updater” migration guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;polyfill-library&lt;/a&gt; received a number of updates (thanks to our open source contributors!)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug where iOS 12 and above would be detected as iOS 11 and we would over-polyfill the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;URL.prototype.toJSON&lt;/code&gt; to now serve to Safari &amp;lt;12 and Edge &amp;lt;18.17134&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MediaQueryList.prototype.addEventListener&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MediaQueryList.prototype.removeEventListener&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Intl.DateTimeFormat.~timeZone.all&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Intl.DateTimeFormat.~timeZone.golden&lt;/code&gt;. The two polyfills can be used to load time-zone data into the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Intl&lt;/code&gt; polyfills - more information can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://formatjs.io/&quot;&gt;formatjs.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/js-features-analyser&quot;&gt;js-features-analyser&lt;/a&gt; fixes a bug where analysing code with destructing assignment would error (thanks to our open source contributors!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-colors&quot;&gt;o-colors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-forms&quot;&gt;o-forms&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-fonts&quot;&gt;o-fonts&lt;/a&gt; have updated migration guides based on feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking&quot;&gt;o-tracking&lt;/a&gt; makes a number of small improvements but notably fixes a bug where click events were lost moving from one page which uses v2 of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-tracking&lt;/code&gt; and the next page which uses v3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Lee Moody</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: New introduction to Origami sessions and special thanks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami npm announcement and guides on how to migrate products</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/07/01/origami-on-npm-and-how-to-migrate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami npm announcement and guides on how to migrate products" /><published>2021-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/07/01/origami-on-npm-and-how-to-migrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/07/01/origami-on-npm-and-how-to-migrate/">&lt;p&gt;We have completed our migration of Origami components from Bower to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot;&gt;NPM registry&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;January’s announcement&lt;/a&gt;). Component releases on Bower are now deprecated and we recommend all products migrate to the new implementation to keep up-to-date with future releases to Origami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami-bower-registry.ft.com/&quot;&gt;FT Bower Registry&lt;/a&gt; has now been placed into a maintenance only mode for 12 months, until 1st July 2022, when we will look to decommission the service completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving Origami from Bower to NPM provides many benefits, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aligning our front-end practices with those now most commonly used across the company and the wider industry, which should help the onboarding of new software engineering hires.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami components can now make use of the 1.6 million packages which are on the NPM registry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami components will be able to use modern tooling instead of the Origami team having to build bespoke tooling ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Services such as Snyk, Dependabot, and Renovate will be able to work for the Origami dependencies a project has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already seeing the benefits with our work on a new autocomplete Origami component, which has been requested by several different FT products. By making this an npm-only component, we’ve been able to benefit from autocomplete packages which already exist on NPM, such as the one made by Gov UK named &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/accessible-autocomplete&quot;&gt;accessible-autocomplete&lt;/a&gt;. This has greatly reduced the amount of code we would have had to write ourselves and meant we could create a prototype for products to trial in a shorter turnaround then previously possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-has-changed-for-origami-users&quot;&gt;What has changed for Origami users?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for Origami components has remained largely the same, aiming to make the migration simpler for our users. The one change we had to make was making the package name for all components now start with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financial-times/&lt;/code&gt;, as they are published under the financial-times namespace on npm. This change means that when importing the javascript and/or sass of a component, you will need to prepend &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financial-times/&lt;/code&gt; to the imported package name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If using Origami components via NPM, it is required to use NPM version 7, this is because version 7 ensures that Origami components are only installed once and no conflicting versions are installed. Origami components do not support using older versions of NPM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those changes don’t affect projects which include Origami components using the Origami Build Service, but there is a new version of the Origami Build Service projects must upgrade to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the below migration guides for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;migration-guides&quot;&gt;Migration Guides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following 3 guides show how to migrate to the new npm-only Origami component releases depending on how your project currently includes components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#using-origami-via-bower&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service&lt;/a&gt;: Follow this guide if your project uses the Origami Build Service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#using-origami-via-origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Bower&lt;/a&gt;: Follow this guide if your project installs components with Bower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#using-origami-via-beta-npm&quot;&gt;Beta NPM&lt;/a&gt;: Follow this guide if your project already installs Origami components via NPM, these were experimental releases which were published to Bower and NPM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-origami-via-origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Using Origami via Origami Build Service&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/url-updater&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service URL Updater&lt;/a&gt; to guide you through the following process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run your project locally in its current state and confirm it is still working correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check your Origami Build Service URL requests the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;latest major Bower release&lt;/a&gt; of each component:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your project already requests the latest Bower release of each component no code changes are required. Otherwise;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your project is using outdated component releases, follow the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;component migration guides&lt;/a&gt; to update to the latest major Bower release.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run your project locally and confirm it is still working correctly. Now you’re ready to do the NPM migration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update your Origami Build Service urls to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/v3/docs/api&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service v3 API&lt;/a&gt; instead of v2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run your project locally and confirm it is still working correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/url-updater&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service URL Updater&lt;/a&gt; to guide you through the migration process in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your migration to npm Origami components is finished! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-origami-via-bower&quot;&gt;Using Origami via Bower&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the project locally in its current state.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check your project installs the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;latest major Bower release&lt;/a&gt; of each component. If your project is using outdated component releases, follow the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;component migration guides&lt;/a&gt; to update to the latest major Bower release.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now you’re ready to do the NPM migration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the project is not using NPM version 7:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clean the directory of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; and any built artefacts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Switch to NPM version 7 and install the dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Confirm the project is still working correctly - If it is not working, try deleting the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package-lock.json&lt;/code&gt; and/or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm-shrinkwrap.json&lt;/code&gt; files and run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; again. There is a known issue with upgrading to NPM version 7 and those files becoming corrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean the directory of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; and any built artefacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install all origami dependencies as npm dependencies and remove them from the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower.json&lt;/code&gt; file. All the components are under the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financialt-times&lt;/code&gt; namespace on NPM. I.E. To install o-table, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install @financial-times/o-table&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If there are still dependencies declared in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower.json&lt;/code&gt; file, try and find the corresponding package on the NPM registry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower.json&lt;/code&gt; file and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bowerrc&lt;/code&gt; file if it exists. E.G. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rm -f .bowerrc bower.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower_components&lt;/code&gt; directory. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rm -rf bower_components&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower&lt;/code&gt; from the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; file. E.G. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm uninstall bower&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update the Sass compiler’s &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;includePath&lt;/code&gt; configuration to include &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; and remove &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bower_components&lt;/code&gt;, then either:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add an additional path &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules/@financial-times&lt;/code&gt; to resolve Sass published under &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financial-times&lt;/code&gt; without specifying a namespace. Or;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Update the Origami Sass imports to include the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financial-times&lt;/code&gt; namespace. E.G. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@import 'o-icons/main';&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@import '@financial-times/o-icons/main';&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update your Origami JavaScript imports to include the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@financial-times&lt;/code&gt; namespace. E.G. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import oTracking from 'o-tracking';&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import oTracking from '@financial-times/o-tracking';&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import 'o-layout';&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import '@financial-times/o-layout';&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the project locally and confirm it is still working correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your migration to npm Origami components is finished! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;using-origami-via-beta-npm&quot;&gt;Using Origami via beta NPM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your project already installs Origami components via NPM, these were experimental releases which were published to Bower and NPM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run your project locally in its current state and confirm it is still working correctly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check your project installs the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;latest major version that was released to Bower&lt;/a&gt; of each component. If your project is using outdated component releases, follow the &lt;a href=&quot;#last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;component migration guides&lt;/a&gt; to update to the latest major release that was Bower-compatible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your project is not using NPM version 7:
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clean the directory of node_modules and any built artefacts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Switch to NPM version 7 and install the dependencies
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Confirm your project is still working correctly - If it is not working, try deleting the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package-lock.json&lt;/code&gt; and/or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm-shrinkwrap.json&lt;/code&gt; files and run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; again. There is a known issue with upgrading to NPM version 7 and those files becoming corrupted.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean the directory of node_modules and any built artefacts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upgrade to the latest major versions of any Origami components you are using&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lockspot&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is-origami-flat&lt;/code&gt;, these should be removed as they are no longer needed when using NPM version 7. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm uninstall lockspot is-origami-flat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run your project locally and confirm it is still working correctly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your migration to npm Origami components is finished! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tracking-migrations&quot;&gt;Tracking migrations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can detect when the relevant repos have been updated to remove Bower. Using that data, we will update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Pem5e6cR0aiuKpYa7VD08AnSSynzjRtWt_VAHAoyhPQ/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;google spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, which contains your projects that are using Origami via Bower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The associated &lt;a href=&quot;https://biz-ops.in.ft.com/Risk/origami-components-via-bower&quot;&gt;entry in the Risk Register&lt;/a&gt; which is linked to all the affected systems that we know of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a breakdown of how many systems and repositories will need to be migrated, split by group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;o-layout__main__single-span&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table class=&quot;o-table o-table--row-headings o-table--horizontal-lines&quot; data-o-component=&quot;o-table&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Group&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Systems to migrate&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Repositories to migrate&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Customer Products&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FT Core&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FT Professional&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Internal Products&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Operations &amp;amp; Reliability&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;last-bower-releases&quot;&gt;Last Bower Releases&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure your project has upgraded to the latest component released to Bower before attempting to migrate to the NPM-only releases. Here is a table of Bower component releases for reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;o-layout__main__single-span&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table class=&quot;o-table o-table--row-headings o-table--vertical-lines o-table--horizontal-lines&quot; data-o-component=&quot;o-table&quot;&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Last Major Bower Release&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Migration Guide&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-autoinit&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-autoinit/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-autoinit migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-banner&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-banner/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-banner migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-big-number&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-big-number/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-big-number migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-brand&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-brand/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-brand migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-buttons&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;6.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-buttons/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-buttons migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-colors&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-colors/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-colors migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-cookie-message&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-cookie-message/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-cookie-message migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-date&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-date/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-date migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-editorial-layout&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-editorial-layout/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-editorial-layout migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-editorial-typography&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-editorial-typography/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-editorial-typography migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-errors&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-errors/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-errors migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-expander&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-expander/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-expander migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-fonts&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-fonts/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-fonts migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-fonts-assets&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-fonts-assets/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-fonts-assets migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-footer&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;7.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-footer/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-footer migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-footer-services&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-footer-services/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-footer-services migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-forms&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-forms/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-forms migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-ft-affiliate-ribbon&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-ft-affiliate-ribbon/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-ft-affiliate-ribbon migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;ftdomdelegate&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/ftdomdelegate/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;ftdomdelegate migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-grid&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-grid/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-grid migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-header&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-header/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-header migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-header-services&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-header-services/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-header-services migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-icons&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;6.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-icons/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-icons migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-labels&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-labels/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-labels migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-layers&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layers/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-layers migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-layout&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-layout migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-lazy-load&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-lazy-load/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-lazy-load migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-loading&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-loading/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-loading migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-message&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-message/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-message migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-meter&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-meter/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-meter migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-normalise&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-normalise/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-normalise migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-overlay&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-overlay/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-overlay migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-quote&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-quote/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-quote migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-share&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;7.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-share/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-share migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-spacing&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-spacing/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-spacing migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-stepped-progress&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-stepped-progress/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-stepped-progress migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-syntax-highlight&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-syntax-highlight/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-syntax-highlight migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-table&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;8.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-table/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-table migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-tabs&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tabs/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-tabs migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-teaser&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;5.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-teaser/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-teaser migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-teaser-collection&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-teaser-collection/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-teaser-collection migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-toggle&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;2.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-toggle/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-toggle migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-tooltip&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tooltip/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-tooltip migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-topper&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-topper/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-topper migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-tracking&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-tracking migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-typography&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;6.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-typography/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-typography migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-utils&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-utils/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-utils migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-viewport&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;4.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-viewport/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-viewport migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;o-visual-effects&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;3.0.0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-visual-effects/blob/master/MIGRATION.md&quot;&gt;o-visual-effects migration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Origami</name></author><summary type="html">We have completed our migration of Origami components from Bower to the NPM registry (see January’s announcement). Component releases on Bower are now deprecated and we recommend all products migrate to the new implementation to keep up-to-date with future releases to Origami.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, June 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/30/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, June 2021" /><published>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/30/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/30/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
TL;DR:
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; Origami via Bower is deprecated, please migrate to the npm versions. A new autocomplete component has been built and is ready for use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ft-bower-registry-is-now-deprecated&quot;&gt;FT Bower Registry is now deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main objective this quarter was to have everything in Origami moved off of Bower and onto the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot;&gt;NPM registry&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;January’s announcement&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving Origami from Bower to NPM provides many benefits, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aligning our front-end practices with those now most commonly used across the company and the wider industry, which should help the on-boarding of new software engineering hires.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami components can now make use of the 1.6 million packages which are on the NPM registry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami components will be able to use modern tooling instead of the Origami team having to build bespoke tooling ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Services such as Snyk, Dependabot, and Renovate will be able to work for the Origami dependencies a project has.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have completed this piece of work and now are ready for teams to migrate their products to the new implementation of Origami. Components on Bower are now deprecated and we recommend all products migrate to the new implementation to keep up-to-date with future releases to Origami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami-bower-registry.ft.com/&quot;&gt;FT Bower Registry&lt;/a&gt; has now also been placed into a maintenance only mode for 12 months, until 1st July 2022, when we will look to decommission the service completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/docs/tutorials/npm/&quot;&gt;created a set of guides&lt;/a&gt; to cover the different ways products may choose to migrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;o-autocomplete&quot;&gt;o-autocomplete&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one of our objectives this quarter was to build an autocomplete/type-ahead component within Origami. This was a component which has been requested by several different FT products. The Product Design team have done a great job on creating an autocomplete design which fits with the rest of the components within our products. We have completed development of the component, which we named &lt;a href=&quot;https://registry.origami.ft.com/components/o-autocomplete&quot;&gt;o-autocomplete&lt;/a&gt;. It is the first component which exists on NPM and not on Bower and it has benefited greatly from this by being able to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/accessible-autocomplete&quot;&gt;accessible-autocomplete&lt;/a&gt; package which already exist on NPM and was made by Gov UK. This greatly reduced the amount of code we would have had to write ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your product is already using an autocomplete component or wanting to use one, we recommend looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://registry.origami.ft.com/components/o-autocomplete&quot;&gt;o-autocomplete&lt;/a&gt; and seeing if you can start using it instead as it is actively being worked on by the Origami and Product Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;origami-build-service-version-2-is-deprecated&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service version 2 is deprecated&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version of the build service uses the now deprecated FT Bower Registry. We have built a new version, version 3, which does not use the FT Bower Registry. To help projects migrate to version 3, we have built &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/url-updater&quot;&gt;a tool&lt;/a&gt; which will list out the specific steps for a project to do in order to successfully migrate over to the new version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are tracking the projects which will need to be migrated to the new version in &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Pem5e6cR0aiuKpYa7VD08AnSSynzjRtWt_VAHAoyhPQ/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;the same spreadshet we are tracking the Bower migration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issues special thanks goes to Xuan Zhang! Xuan worked on the design and interactions for the new o-autocomplete component and was very helpful in explaining the designs and how they should look on different devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAJOR: All Origami maintained components have been migrated from Bower to NPM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAJOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt; version 11 released, dropping support for Bower and adding full support for NPM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-colors&quot;&gt;o-colors&lt;/a&gt; added a new palette named “partner content” with a new colour named “Matisse”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout&quot;&gt;o-layout&lt;/a&gt; added missing closing div to the footer markup in the component’s demos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-teaser&quot;&gt;o-teaser&lt;/a&gt; updated the partner content label colour to “matisse”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layers&quot;&gt;o-layers&lt;/a&gt; was deprecated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking&quot;&gt;o-tracking&lt;/a&gt; has added back the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;source_id&lt;/code&gt; property&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Origami blog now has &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/feed.xml&quot;&gt;an RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service&lt;/a&gt; version 3 was released along with a page to help projects update their URLs to use the latest version of Origami&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following projects have had additional updates to support the migration from Bower to NPM:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-service&quot;&gt;Polyfill Service&lt;/a&gt; has migrated to using Origami components via NPM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service&lt;/a&gt; has migrated to using Origami components via NPM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&quot;&gt;Origami Repo Data&lt;/a&gt; has migrated to using Origami components via NPM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-workshop&quot;&gt;Origami Workshop&lt;/a&gt; has migrated to using Origami components via NPM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/create-origami-component&quot;&gt;Create Origami Component&lt;/a&gt; has been updated to create an Origami component which publishes to NPM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&quot;&gt;Origami Repo Data&lt;/a&gt; was updated to handle NPM components as well as Bower components&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;Polyfill Library&lt;/a&gt;’s internationalisation polyfills have been updated to include more timezones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Origami team</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: Origami via Bower is deprecated, please migrate to the npm versions. A new autocomplete component has been built and is ready for use.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, May 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/01/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, May 2021" /><published>2021-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/01/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/06/01/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
TL;DR:
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; The Origami specification is no more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-origami-specification-is-no-more&quot;&gt;The Origami specification is no more&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team spent most of the month revisiting the &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/spec/v1/&quot;&gt;Origami Specification&lt;/a&gt;. The specification is a formal document detailing the rules of how an Origami project, such as a component, must be built. We were trying to separate the parts of it that were developer advice from the parts that were relied on by our tools and services. After reducing the specification from 35 pages to 3, we had one last meeting in which we ultimately decided to retire the specification entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-people-mean-when-they-say-origami&quot;&gt;What do people mean when they say Origami?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When other teams say Origami, they tend to mean either the FT’s design or our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we say Origami we tend to mean our reference implementation of the brand guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-benefit-of-the-specification&quot;&gt;What is the benefit of the specification?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Origami was originally conceived as a series of specifications for components and services. There was an expectation that people all over the company and at external agencies would be building new Origami components and services all the time. In that context, a shared contract made a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not how it ended up. Origami components are mostly built by our team, and we’re always in the loop when other teams build Origami components. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams don’t trust the specification, they trust &lt;strong&gt;us&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specification wasn’t what kept our components working in all the environments they were used in: we did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve always been vigilant about not breaking things for people, and that will never change. Breaking changes will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; happen in major versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retiring the specification gives us the opportunity to create better, faster, more modern components and to make sure that Design are a leading part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be going into a lot more detail about our plans in a blog post at the end of Q2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This issues special thanks goes to Nick Ramsbottom! Nick worked with us on a component update to support New Product Development work, and enthusiastically got involved in the development. Together we were able to avoid project-specific overrides for a more reliable, consistent user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your team are looking to customise an Origami component for a project, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/docs/components/customisation/&quot;&gt;guide to component customisation&lt;/a&gt; or contact the team for support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened since our last update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/podcast-logos&quot;&gt;podcast-logos&lt;/a&gt;, podcast logos are no longer updated in Origami, refer to Acast, the podcast hosting system we use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-colors&quot;&gt;o-colors&lt;/a&gt; adds a new “matisse” colour, which is used by partner content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-forms&quot;&gt;o-forms&lt;/a&gt; provide styling for a file upload input &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;input[type=&quot;file&quot;]&lt;/code&gt; 🎉, and fixes the low contrast of valid form fields for the whitelabel brand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-labels&quot;&gt;o-labels&lt;/a&gt; adds a wider selection of labels for the internal brand, using colours from our palette.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout&quot;&gt;o-layout&lt;/a&gt; fixes an issue where the “muted hero” area was obscured by the page background colour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tooltip&quot;&gt;o-tooltip&lt;/a&gt; adds Sass customisation options, including foreground and background colours. Thanks again, Nick Ramsbottom!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;polyfill-library&lt;/a&gt; adds a polyfill for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HTMLInputElement.prototype.valueAsDate&lt;/code&gt;, fix a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library/issues/1048&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;URLSearchParams&lt;/code&gt; bug&lt;/a&gt;, and more (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library/releases&quot;&gt;polyfill-library releases&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/change-api-action&quot;&gt;change-api-action&lt;/a&gt; only adds &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;githubname&lt;/code&gt; to the change api payload if the action was triggered by a github user, this fixes the action when trigged at set intervals by a cron for example.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-grid&quot;&gt;o-grid&lt;/a&gt; fixes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-grid.layoutChange&lt;/code&gt; events given custom layouts (breakpoints). Thanks for your help with that, Eray Baskin!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-table&quot;&gt;o-table&lt;/a&gt; fixes the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;updateRows&lt;/code&gt; method to account for removed or changed rows. Thanks Emma Lewis for your work investigating that one!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-percy&quot;&gt;origami-percy&lt;/a&gt; is used for component visual regression testing, it’s now more reliable and will not error if no component demos are found for a supported brand. In addition it runs automatically for each component now and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;percy&lt;/code&gt; Github label, which used to trigger tests, has been removed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/useragent_parser&quot;&gt;useragent_parser&lt;/a&gt; updates the detection logic for more accurate reporting of ios 11 and newer versions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://registry.origami.ft.com/components&quot;&gt;Origami Registry&lt;/a&gt; now shows stable releases of components by default. Use the version switcher in the right-hand sidebar to preview upcoming beta releases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following projects have had additional updates to support the &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;migration from bower to NPM&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&quot;&gt;origami-repo-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-website&quot;&gt;origami-website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-test-component&quot;&gt;o-test-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;origami-build-service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/create-origami-component&quot;&gt;create-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/remark-preset-lint-origami-component&quot;&gt;remark-preset-lint-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>chee rabbits, lee moody</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: The Origami specification is no more</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, March 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/04/12/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, March 2021" /><published>2021-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/04/12/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/04/12/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
TL;DR:
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; Updated Origami workshops. Work has begun to migrate Origami to npm. Reminder, we deprecate FT’s Bower Registry in July. 2021 and plan to decomission in July 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-on-the-migration-to-npm-dropping-bower-support&quot;&gt;Update on the migration to npm (dropping Bower support)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During January we announced our plan to &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/#who-does-this-affect&quot;&gt;decommission the FT Bower Registry and migrate to the public npm registry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work has now started on migrating the Origami components onto npm, 8 out of 66 of our component are now migrated, ready to be released. We aim to have all components, including documentation/guidance for how to migrate your products, complete by the start of Q3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, below is a copy of our planned timeline to decommission the FT Bower Registry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2021 - Origami Components moved from Bower to npm and guides to migrate are written&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2021 - Deprecate the FT Bower Registry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2022 - Decommission the FT Bower Registry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-introduction-to-origami-dates&quot;&gt;New “Introduction to Origami” dates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please join us on 26th April for updated Introduction to Origami sessions! ✨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 1 is useful for anyone who works in Product and Technology – we cover things at a high level rather than diving into too many technical details, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami History&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 2 will explore components in more depth, including some technical details. It will be of particular interest to engineers and designers, although anyone is welcome:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Languages &amp;amp; Tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versioning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Origami Build Service / Manual Build&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practical Tutorial (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be running these on the 26th April, at a time suitable for London and Sofia. We’ll share a recording for those who can’t make it, but it would be great to see you there! Please let us know if you or someone on your team would like an invite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guidance-on-how-to-customise-an-origami-component&quot;&gt;Guidance on how to customise an Origami component&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have a page to help our users decide if they need to customise an Origami component, and if so, how to go about it in a safe, supported way which should reduce the chance of the customisation breaking in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/docs/components/customisation/&quot;&gt;have a read through the page&lt;/a&gt; and let us know of any feedback you may have or suggestions for other topics we could write guidance for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had an uptick in the amount of security researchers wanting to submit reports about potential issues on &lt;a href=&quot;https://polyfill.io&quot;&gt;polyfill.io&lt;/a&gt;. We’d like to thank the Cyber Security team for communicating with the security researchers and reviewing their reports for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-fonts&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-fonts&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;FinancierDisplayWeb was added to support Specialist Titles&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-layout&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To support the ongoing microsite project, o-layout now support the master brand for default, bleed, documentation layouts.
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Support was also added for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; element in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-layout-typography&lt;/code&gt; wrapper.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-tracking&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A couple of bugs were found and fixed which were sending invalid or duplicate events to Spoor:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Duplicate click events from multiple browser contexts&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Fix bug where loading spoor-id from the cookie would silently fail&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-build-service&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Several updates were made in preparation for origami components being on npm:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Added autoprefixer for css and using the same browser config as origami-build-tools.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Only allows @financial-times namespaced components to be requested in v3.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Renamed the modules and module query parameters to components and component in v3.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Implemented the /v3/demo and /v3/demo/html endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A security vulnerability was found and fixed by the Origami team:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Deprecated the use of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;modules&lt;/code&gt; for anything that’s not in the allow-list.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;obt test --debug&lt;/code&gt; watch for changes and rebuild tests.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Several updates were made in preparation for origami components being on npm:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Add validation for package.json.browser field&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Add validation for package.json.name field&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Improve tests for verify-package-json&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Remove unused component fixture&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Verify package.json manifest has description and keywords&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;expect origamiVersion to be the “2.0” string&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Several updates were made in preparation for origami components being on npm:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Only read &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;keywords&lt;/code&gt; property from the package.json manifest and not origami.json or bower.json&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Allow origami version to be the “2.0” string&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;use v3 of the build service for spec v2 components&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Correct the languages property of spec v2 component versions&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/create-origami-component&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/create-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Several updates were made in preparation for origami components being on npm:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Moved description and keywords to the package.json instead of origami.json&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/polyfill-library&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Added a polyfill for Element.prototype.getAttributeNames&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-message&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-message&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Match padding left and right given a close button and centred message&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Align feedback notices centre when there is one line of copy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-forms&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-forms&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allow multi-line box-style radio button copy, making them taller.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transparent radio buttons can make them look inactive&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add a white background to internal brand radio inputs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-topper&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-topper&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Include default link style for toppers with colour&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-share&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-share&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make the new corporate icon from fticons available in o-share&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jake Champion</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: Updated Origami workshops. Work has begun to migrate Origami to npm. Reminder, we deprecate FT’s Bower Registry in July. 2021 and plan to decomission in July 2022.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, February 2021</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/03/02/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, February 2021" /><published>2021-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/03/02/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/03/02/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
TL;DR:
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; This issue is a big one. It covers our progress toward the recently announced npm migration; a new Origami Image Service placeholder image feature; a new Origami Build Service feature to help teams keep components up to date; and a whole bunch more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news since our last issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dropping-bower-support&quot;&gt;Dropping Bower Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been making excellent progress towards migrating Origami components from Bower to the npmjs registry. Origami tooling has been updated, and services such as the Origami Build Service are almost ready too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the release of npm7 &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2020/10/28/newsletter/#new-proposal-to-drop-bower-support&quot;&gt;we think now is a good time to drop Bower support&lt;/a&gt;. To find out what it means for your team, and what benefits we hope to achieve, see &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;last month’s announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;placeholder-images&quot;&gt;Placeholder Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/&quot;&gt;Origami Image Service&lt;/a&gt; can now generate placeholder images at specified dimensions and quality. It’s a super useful feature to support prototypes and testing. 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example placeholder request, for an image that’s 500px square, of maximum quality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/placeholder/?width=500&amp;amp;height=500&amp;amp;quality=lossless&amp;amp;source=test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/placeholder/?width=500&amp;amp;height=500&amp;amp;quality=lossless&amp;amp;source=test&quot; alt=&quot;A placeholder image which displays the width, height, format, and quality of the image requested as text within the image.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;build-service-updater&quot;&gt;Build Service Updater&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/&quot;&gt;Origami Build Service&lt;/a&gt; helps teams include &lt;a href=&quot;https://registry.origami.ft.com/components&quot;&gt;components&lt;/a&gt; in projects quickly, without having to worry about setting up potentially complicated build steps. However it can be tricky to know when a Build Service request is out of date, and including old versions of components which could be upgraded. Now the Build Service has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/build/url-updater&quot;&gt;URL updater page&lt;/a&gt; which can check a Build Service URL and let you know which of your components are out of date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://origami.ft.com/assets/images/2021-03-02-newsletter/build-service-updater.png?quality=highest&amp;amp;source=origami&quot; alt=&quot;The Build Service updater. For a given Build Service URL it displays a table of requested components which shows the requested version, the latest version, whether it is out of date or not, and where to find migration guides to upgrade as required.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to Erin Ferguson for helping us write &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;last month’s announcement&lt;/a&gt; and for organising training for the team, we can’t wait and look forward to sharing what we learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened since our last issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DEPRECATED: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-assets&quot;&gt;o-assets&lt;/a&gt; has been deprecated since it is not used widely and will no longer work for npm only components. There is a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/pull/102&quot;&gt;proposal for how we could build with unique component assets&lt;/a&gt; in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MAJOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-test-component&quot;&gt;o-test-component&lt;/a&gt; has been updated to follow V2 of the Origami Specification, which drops support for Bower. It will support the testing of Origami tools and services as we migrate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-footer-services&quot;&gt;o-footer-services&lt;/a&gt; adds “a Nikkei company” brand strip, similar to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-footer&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-icons&quot;&gt;o-icons&lt;/a&gt; adds a label, label outline, and restore icon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-share&quot;&gt;o-share&lt;/a&gt; adds a new “corporate” share icon to support an experimental enterprise feature, super-gifting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking&quot;&gt;o-tracking&lt;/a&gt; improves efficiency when multiple calls are made to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;oTracking.click.init&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;origami-build-service&lt;/a&gt; has had some significant updates. First, we identified and fixed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-community/attacks/xss/&quot;&gt;cross site scripting&lt;/a&gt; vulnerability in the demos endpoint — did you know &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/book/id/v2/GitHub-Maintaining-a-Project&quot;&gt;Github adds references for forked pull requests to your repository&lt;/a&gt;? Second, we have an experimental V3 api (a work in progress) which will support &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/&quot;&gt;npm only Origami components&lt;/a&gt; and drop features we no longer require. Third, we added the URL Updater discussed above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-image-service&quot;&gt;origami-image-service&lt;/a&gt; adds a new placeholder feature, as discussed above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-labels&quot;&gt;origami-labels&lt;/a&gt; adds support for beta releases (when working on an Origami component you can now add a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;release: beta&lt;/code&gt; github label to release a beta version on merge).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-specialist-title-logos&quot;&gt;origami-specialist-title-logos&lt;/a&gt; adds FT Forums logos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;Polyfill Service&lt;/a&gt; has seen a number of improvements since our last update.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Improvements in CI: Dramatically reduced the time it takes to complete by only testing the polyfills which have changed. Updated to test against the latest versions of all browsers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;New polyfills: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Element.prototype.getAttributeNames&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HTMLSelectElement.prototype.selectedOptions&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;URL.prototype.toJSON&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-colors&quot;&gt;o-colors&lt;/a&gt; ensures saturation and luminance values are percentages to stop Sass deprecation warnings from being emitted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-cookie-message&quot;&gt;o-cookie-message&lt;/a&gt; prevents &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.dev/bfcache/&quot;&gt;back/forward cache&lt;/a&gt; from showing the cookie message after a reader has already accepted or rejected cookies (credit to Oliver, nice!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-grid&quot;&gt;o-grid&lt;/a&gt; is less annoying. Did this Sass warning get you down?  “WARNING: The ‘snappy’ grid mode is deprecated and will be removed in the next major version of o-grid…” We’ve removed the warning since the snappy grid is still used on the stream and article pages of ft.com, with no immediate plans to redesign them for the default, fluid grid which new projects use. Warnings should be useful, not frustrating.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout&quot;&gt;o-layout&lt;/a&gt; fixes overflow on viewports smaller than the max container width, where content may wrap or scroll instead.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-topper&quot;&gt;o-topper&lt;/a&gt; has received a number of visual improvements and bug fixes. Thanks Keran (😭🇨🇦), Gus, and Nick for your work on that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-video&quot;&gt;o-video&lt;/a&gt; fixes a bug which caused video playback to hang when ads failed to load (thanks again to Gus for that one).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To support the switch to npm more Origami tools and services have been updated or received major/beta releases, including:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/create-origami-component&quot;&gt;create-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-bundle-size-cli&quot;&gt;origami-bundle-size-cli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-ci-tools&quot;&gt;origami-ci-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-percy&quot;&gt;origami-percy&lt;/a&gt;, Origami’s visual regression tester&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-version&quot;&gt;origami-version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/remark-preset-lint-origami-component&quot;&gt;remark-preset-lint-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Lee Moody</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: This issue is a big one. It covers our progress toward the recently announced npm migration; a new Origami Image Service placeholder image feature; a new Origami Build Service feature to help teams keep components up to date; and a whole bunch more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Migrating Origami Components to npm and Deprecating the FT Bower Registry</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrating Origami Components to npm and Deprecating the FT Bower Registry" /><published>2021-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2021/01/18/deprecating-bower-and-origami-via-npm/">&lt;p&gt;We are migrating Origami Components from Bower onto the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot;&gt;npmjs registry&lt;/a&gt;, this will be done by the end of Q2. Once the Origami Components are on npm, the versions on Bower will go into a deprecated state where they have no new features added. Products/Projects which want to get new Origami designs and features will need to migrate to npm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also deprecating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami-bower-registry.ft.com/&quot;&gt;Bower Registry&lt;/a&gt;, it will be placed into a maintenance only mode for 12 months and then we will look to decommission the service completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend that all products/projects which use Bower migrate over to using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot;&gt;npmjs registry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-the-origami-team-provide-migration-support&quot;&gt;Will the Origami team provide migration support?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the team has done several migrations of our services and components in the past and know that helping our users migrate is very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be providing migration guides for every individual Origami component, as we have done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will also provide written guidance on how to migrate a project from Origami via Bower to Origami via npmjs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are contactable via the Slack channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://financialtimes.slack.com/archives/C02FU5ARJ&quot;&gt;#origami-support&lt;/a&gt; if you want to speak to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For teams which have too much to migrate on their own, we may be able to help migrate your products for you. If you would like our help migrating your products, please let us know in advance as there are only 3 of us, we won't be able to help every team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-timeline-for-this-work&quot;&gt;What is the timeline for this work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2021 - Origami Components moved from Bower to npm and guides to migrate are written&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2021 - Deprecate the FT Bower Registry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st July 2022 - Decommission the FT Bower Registry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-does-this-affect&quot;&gt;Who does this affect?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This affects every product/project which uses the FT Bower Registry. We've done a search across the entire Financial-Times GitHub account and collated all the projects which are affected and will need to migrate to an alternative Bower registry or off Bower completely. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Pem5e6cR0aiuKpYa7VD08AnSSynzjRtWt_VAHAoyhPQ/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;google spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; contains all the systems which are affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-i-need-to-do-anything-right-now&quot;&gt;Do I need to do anything right now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No you do not. If you are using any Origami Components via the Bower Registry then you will need to wait until we have migrated those Origami Components to the npmjs registry, which should be complete by the end of Q2. We will have guides on how to migrate from Bower to npm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-timeeffort-will-i-need-to-allocate-to-this-q3-onward&quot;&gt;How much time/effort will I need to allocate to this Q3 onward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time/effort varies drastically across products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know this will be a very big effort for Customer Products because they have many things on Bower themselves as well as having abstractions on top of Origami which will need to be migrated before they can migrate their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Internal Products the effort should be smaller than Customer Products because they don't have extra abstractions to migrate first before migrating their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For FT Professional the effort should be the same as Internal Products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a breakdown of how many systems and repositories will need to be migrated, split by group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;o-layout__main__single-span&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table class=&quot;o-table o-table--row-headings o-table--horizontal-lines&quot; data-o-component=&quot;o-table&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Group&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Systems to migrate&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Repositories to migrate&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Customer Products&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FT Core&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;FT Professional&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Internal Products&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Operations &amp;amp; Reliability&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-you-tracking-the-migration-progress&quot;&gt;How are you tracking the migration progress?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can detect when the relevant repos have been updated to remove Bower. Using that data, once a week we will update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1Pem5e6cR0aiuKpYa7VD08AnSSynzjRtWt_VAHAoyhPQ/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;google spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt;, which contains the data for the table above.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The associated &lt;a href=&quot;https://biz-ops.in.ft.com/Risk/origami-components-via-bower&quot;&gt;entry in the Risk Register&lt;/a&gt; which is linked to all the affected systems that we know of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-this-happening&quot;&gt;Why is this happening?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The front-end community at large has already moved away from using Bower for their projects and has moved to using npm. This change can also be seen within the FT, as some individual teams have already moved onto npm. Due to fewer projects using Bower, the amount of infrastructure and tooling which exists that supports Bower has been decreasing or not been kept up-to-date with the advancements in the rest of the front-end industry. Origami has had to invest lots of time and energy into creating new tools and infrastructure to support Bower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Origami project was stuck using Bower due to other software registries not having the features that Origami required. This is no longer the case with the latest release of npm. With the Origami project migrating off Bower and onto npm, it enables us to deprecate the Bower Registry and accompanying infrastructure and tooling which has become a large piece of technical debt we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-benefits-does-this-give-the-ft&quot;&gt;What benefits does this give the FT?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saving £1,200 per month from our Heroku bill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This will align the FT's front-end practices with those now most commonly used across the industry which will help improve the onboarding of new hires to projects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Origami project will be able to use many of the 1.5 million packages which exist on the npmjs registry, greatly reducing the amount of code/features we currently have to write ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Origami team will be able to invest more time on the Origami project and services, which are used across many of the FT Group's products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It will be easier for our engineers to get started using or contributing to the Origami project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Jake Champion</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">We are migrating Origami Components from Bower onto the npmjs registry, this will be done by the end of Q2. Once the Origami Components are on npm, the versions on Bower will go into a deprecated state where they have no new features added. Products/Projects which want to get new Origami designs and features will need to migrate to npm.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, December 2020</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/29/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, December 2020" /><published>2020-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/29/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/29/newsletter/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-and-vision-statements&quot;&gt;Mission and Vision Statements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back over the 7 years of the team and project, we wrote a new mission statement for Origami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve posted them on the website here: https://origami.ft.com/docs/principles/vision-and-mission/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mission&quot;&gt;Mission&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unifying and documenting the style and experience across the digital products of every FT brand, leveraging the web platform to provide an implementation of the brand guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to ensure our mission statement expresses that Origami is for every person and every product in the whole FT Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vision&quot;&gt;Vision&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every designer and developer in the FT knows how to use Origami, feels they have the agency to contribute to Origami and that they are an owner of Origami.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Origami is the gold standard of design systems and every FT designer and developer’s favourite way to create digital products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Terry Pratchett’s Hogfather, Death says “HUMANS NEED FANTASY IN ORDER TO BE HUMAN. TO BE THE PLACE WHERE THE FALLING ANGEL MEETS THE RISING APE”. At the Strata Data Conference in 2019, Cait O’Riordan said it’s important to find your North Star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vision statement is like that. It’s where we want to be, it helps guide our choices so that one day it might be where we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now our focus is on making Origami feel like a project owned by everyone, something everyone wants to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still some ways off, but we’re looking forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-end-of-year-clean-up&quot;&gt;An end-of-year clean up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we closed around 700 issues on Origami projects on GitHub. It’s the first time we’ve had fewer than 300 things on our team todo list. We’ll continue to reduce that number, making it easier to plan our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🧹&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also archived the project &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-gallery&lt;/code&gt;, which was no longer in use and had not received updates in some time. We hope to replace it with a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/issues/23&quot;&gt;carousel component&lt;/a&gt; in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-plan-for-the-year-ahead&quot;&gt;A plan for the year ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work continues on the proposal to modernise Origami by dropping support for &lt;a href=&quot;https://bower.io/&quot;&gt;bower&lt;/a&gt; and shipping our components only via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our current roadmap has us deprecating our bower components at the end of Q2, and putting them in maintenance mode for a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank-you everyone for helping each other make it through this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FmuswTEGF-U&quot;&gt;Happy new year.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-service&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/polyfill-service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;RangeError: Malformed unicode_language_subtag on Intl polyfill&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add Intl.Locale and other Intl.* Polyfills&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[Bug] Chrome/49 - Cannot redefine property: hasInstance&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[feature] missing String.replaceAll polyfill&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[Bug] Chrome/49 - Cannot redefine property: isConcatSpreadable&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Feature Request: list popular polyfills&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Enable The ‘unicorn/no-reduce’ rule&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;enable unicorn/no-reduce&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/polyfill-library&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update smoothscroll detect logic&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Allow getters and setters to be set to undefined and not throw an error&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix test polyfill timeout&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;compress test server responses and add test matrix with partial retries&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix linter errors&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;TypedArray polyfills are included for every browser target&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update targeting for TypedArray polyfills&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update yaku version to v1.0.0&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Feature Request: Navigator.permissions API polyfill?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;make sure errors contain useful messages&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add ability to generate sourcemaps&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;rel=preload support?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Feature Request - Add Dialog polyfill&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[feature-request] lazy loading support&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[feature-request] Proxy polyfill&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;[Feature Request] Given a browser matrix, output the suite of polyfills per browser for every version that satisfies the matrix&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;add “es2015” to the aliases of String.fromCodePoint&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;update polyfill configs for edge 79 + a few corrections&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix Symbol.prototype.description&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fetch polyfill is no longer spec compliant&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Reflect fixes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Array fixes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;isolate test runs with and without polyfill combinations&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix URL polyfill by no longer overwriting it in the Blob polyfill&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix StringIndexOf&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Object fixes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;WeakMap fixes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix unterminated polyfills.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Serve DOMRect polyfill to Edge versions &amp;lt; 79&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-image-service&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-image-service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update troubleshooting section for SVGs to mention it applies to all SVG requests&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Custom schemes (not including ftcms) should use cloudinary upload instead of fetch&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Consider using quality:auto&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Use the explicit API to clear the cache&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Missing source attribute in prefilled form without image url&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;only delete formData.source if we set it&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Make the purging endpoint also purge from cloudinary&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library-node&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/polyfill-library-node&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add missing Origami GH Actions and labels&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add codeowners, issue template and publishing step&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-service&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-build-service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Error if no brand query parameter&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Backport conflicts work to Build Service v2&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Feature: add support for spec v2 origami components&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Issue: ESM module support&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Error if no source query parameter&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Disable adding Babel polyfills by default&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add v3/files endpoint&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Do not crash the app if the NPM cache fails to prime.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Error page for conflicts is hard to read&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Wrap error messages in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pre&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add middleware to ensure all requested Origami modules are built using the same Origami Specification version&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update website to use o-layout and add v3 endpoints for bundling&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-imageset-data&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-imageset-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Migrate from CircleCI to GitHub Workflows&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-labels&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-labels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;turn off github-label-sync action’s deletion of unknown labels&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Allow arbitrary labels to be added&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;proposal: add an accessibility label&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;add an accessibility label&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-website&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add the mission and vision statements to the front page&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add mission and vision statements to the homepage&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add Origami type&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Avoid “we”/”let’s” in tutorials?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Bump remark-preset-lint-origami-component version&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Tidy up test output&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Automatically run verify before test&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Require component lint configuration&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Only lint files if the component itself contains linting config for those file types&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;pass through the ignore bower flag when building the pa11y demo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/remark-preset-lint-origami-component&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/remark-preset-lint-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Remove whitespace from action name&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Correct package.json version.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add publish to npm workflow&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-useragent-normaliser&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/polyfill-useragent-normaliser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;move to github actions&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Move the circleci jobs into github workflows&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-registry-ui&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-registry-ui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update to npm 7&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fails to deploy to staging due to a dart-sass shell bug&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Improve Origami service discoverability&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Replace origamiType checkboxes with radio buttons&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Show radio buttons for origamiType instead of checkboxes&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Work out how we display whether a version of a component builds or not&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Investigate unreliable demo iframe resizing&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;include services in the default search filter&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-fonts&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-fonts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Map the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;light&lt;/code&gt; font weight to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;300&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Map a “light” font weight to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;300 instead of &lt;/code&gt;200`&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-brand-images&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-brand-images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Can we deprecate this?&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Deprecate the image set as it is not being used anymore&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-gallery&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Is not silent mode by default (scss)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Component redesign&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/js-features-analyser&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/js-features-analyser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;How to use with browserlist and a polyfill library&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Data source of global-static-instance.json&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-buttons&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-buttons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Right align button icons&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-editorial-layout&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-editorial-layout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;style nested &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;strong&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;em&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sup&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sub&lt;/code&gt; tags within &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; tags.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Improve adoption of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-editorial-layout&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-teaser-collection&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-teaser-collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;o-teaser-collection&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-navigation-data&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-navigation-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ACC-764 Revert “Revert “ACC-764 add Contact Us to footer””&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Revert “ACC-764 add Contact Us to footer”&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;ACC-764 add Contact Us to footer&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add Work &amp;amp; Careers in place of Graphics&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;remove graphics link from top level navigation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-ads-embed&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-ads-embed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Remove unnecessary heavy ads monitoring&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Attempt to monitor heavy ad interventions by Chrome&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-specialist-title-logos&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-specialist-title-logos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Deprecate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brand-live-ft-logo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Deprecate brand-live-ft-logo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-image-set-tools&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-image-set-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;test on node 10, 12 and 14&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-topper&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-topper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Stop changing background wheat to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;oColorsMix($color: 'wheat', $percentage: 40)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Currently fails pa11y tests&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/github-label-sync&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/github-label-sync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add an option to run for all repositories in a user or organisation&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Merging labels doesn’t seem to work&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-video&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;oVideo to support slot level override of config (mix and match global + data attribute config)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;We should track buffering events&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Track &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;waiting&lt;/code&gt; event&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;iOS doesn’t like firing progress events&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Move o-video advertising code to o-ads&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-icons&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add o-icon-small-icon classes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-forms&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-forms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add better error styles for whitelabel brand in inverse mode&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add support for inverse form fields and error messaging&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add inverse form support for radios, checkboxes and error states and summaries&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Improve radio box input given long labels&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-overlay&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-overlay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Expose the overlay instance on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;oOverlay.ready&lt;/code&gt; event&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Expose overlay on the ready event detail&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Remove any characters that aren’t valid when generating a heading id.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Remove non-ascii alphanumericals when generating heading id&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Jumping around on iPad&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tracking&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-tracking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Question - use of data-trackable with &lt;a&gt; where target is blank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-share&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Possible to include sticky behaviour&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;fix the demos so they compile for the internal brand&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-tooltip&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-tooltip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add an option to hide when leaving hover&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Enforce accessibility best practices by making some parameters mandatory&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Expose current release number to the component’s own code&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;A Carousel component&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Provide a way to express that a component is safe to be used with any brand.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Review how we manage and deploy component specifc assets&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Make our whitelabel components easier to theme for build service users&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Autocomplete&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;New Component: Tag Input&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;feedback component&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;A slider component&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Opting elements into dark mode via a parent selector&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Proposal: perform a review of the Origami spec&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Proposal: npm-only origami components&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-repo-data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Support NPM(only) Components&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;origamiVersion&lt;/code&gt; filter to the repos endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add origami version to version entity&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Update test expectations for a peer dependency&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;isPeer&lt;/code&gt; to the Dependency Entity.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-toggle&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-toggle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Provide the ability to switch the button text at the same time as the display&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-message&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Correct access annotation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-meter&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/o-meter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add pa11y demo to tested demos&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Fix pa11y demo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Add back the pa11y demo&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-ci-tools&quot;&gt;Financial-Times/origami-ci-tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Run pa11y against all supported brands&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Stop building the pa11y demo separately as obt test builds the pa11y demo now&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make getDataAttributes ignore data attributes which are not in the component’s namespace&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>chee</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">Top things</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Origami Newsletter, November 2020</title><link href="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/01/newsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Origami Newsletter, November 2020" /><published>2020-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/01/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://origami.ft.com/blog/2020/12/01/newsletter/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;Too long; didn't read&quot;&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;
	TL;DR:
	&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/abbr&gt; This issue features Engine Room, Origami v2, and on-site messaging bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;top-things&quot;&gt;Top Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the bigger Origami news from the last month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;engine-room&quot;&gt;Engine Room&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month Origami team member Lee (oh hey, that’s me!) gave a talk “&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1eiVw1-zhMSRy8S-5--xQJeBcYg_j17A6/view&quot;&gt;Origami: Past, Present, &amp;amp; Future&lt;/a&gt;” at &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/ft.com/engine-room-live/&quot;&gt;Engine Room&lt;/a&gt;, the FT’s engineering-focused, internal conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk covers a little history including why Origami exists, how Origami has adapted to new needs over the last 7 years, and gives a little peek at what’s to come. There are plenty of new opportunities for us to share and build on each others good work. The talk touches on a few technical subjects but is suitable for anyone within product and technology. If you missed it a &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1eiVw1-zhMSRy8S-5--xQJeBcYg_j17A6/view&quot;&gt;recording is available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Engine Room recordings are available in &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1c84vnejFTdDeIK5RGS9BdMOQYEiOGRCl&quot;&gt;Google drive&lt;/a&gt;. There are many excellent talks to explore for those who couldn’t make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;origami-v2&quot;&gt;Origami V2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work continues on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/pull/86&quot;&gt;proposal to drop Bower support in favour of NPM&lt;/a&gt;. By switching we will align with the broader tech ecosystem and help speed up development at the FT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we’ve tested out the proposed approach and… it works 🎉 We have also created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-website/pull/273&quot;&gt;draft Origami v2 specification&lt;/a&gt; with the changes required to drop Bower support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proposal affects all projects which depend on Origami components. If you have any questions, thoughts, or feedback we’d love to hear in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.slack.com/client/T025C95MN/CSW6B2VAN&quot;&gt;#origami-chat&lt;/a&gt; Slack channel or as a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/pull/86&quot;&gt;the proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know this is one many of our engineers are excited about. Thanks to everyone who has given us feedback so far, it’s much appreciated. 👏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-site-messaging&quot;&gt;On-Site Messaging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the design team we released a minor update to &lt;a href=&quot;https://registry.origami.ft.com/components/o-message@4.2.3&quot;&gt;o-message&lt;/a&gt; this month, which fixes some visual bugs including improvements to spacing around message content. We’re careful not to release breaking changes within minor releases but unfortunately messaging on some projects broke as they were heavily customising &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-message&lt;/code&gt; in an unsupported way, with CSS overrides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response we offered to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/next-article/pull/4055&quot;&gt;help update how projects use o-message&lt;/a&gt; to fix the problem. In addition, Xuan and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.slack.com/client/T025C95MN/C01481FKWA2&quot;&gt;#design-ops&lt;/a&gt; team are auditing our on-site messaging currently so we can update &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-message&lt;/code&gt; and other Origami components to meet our current needs consistently, without the use of overrides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overriding component styles with CSS can be problematic for a few reasons. It introduces design inconsistency, code complexity, and fragility (overrides are liable to break without warning when components are updated, as happened in this case). Instead it’s better to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work with the design team to decide whether a component really needs a unique modification (see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.slack.com/client/T025C95MN/C01481FKWA2&quot;&gt;#design-ops&lt;/a&gt; Slack channel).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update the component to include the new style.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add new Sass options so the component can be customised.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or, if you’re after quite different features or a whole new look, build from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Origami team are here to help you decide which option is right for your project and make component updates if needed. We’re also happy to help you review a projects use of components, to remove duplication and overrides — let us know how we can help in &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.slack.com/client/T025C95MN/C02FU5ARJ&quot;&gt;#origami-support&lt;/a&gt; 😊&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-thanks&quot;&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we’ve made more direct contributions to Customer Products projects than usual. Our special thanks goes to those who helped review and release our work quickly so we could move on to other tasks. That includes Nick Colley and Simon Plenderleith, thanks both! 🙏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-update&quot;&gt;Broader Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A digest of other things that have happened this month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami&quot;&gt;Origami Proposals&lt;/a&gt;: This month there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/pull/93&quot;&gt;new proposal to rename the Origami team&lt;/a&gt;. There is also an update on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/pull/92&quot;&gt;variable font proposal&lt;/a&gt; — since we can only commission a resized MetricWeb variable font the work required for the proposal is greater, but as a bonus we may be able to reduce the complexity and increase the reliability of our font loading strategy. Let us know what you think!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-website&quot;&gt;Origami Specification&lt;/a&gt;: we’ve updated the Origami specification to relax some rules. Components without Sass may support brands without including &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-brand&lt;/code&gt; as a dependency; Sass lint rules may be customised with a Style Lint configuration &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.stylelintrc.js&lt;/code&gt;; we’ve also been working on the v2 draft specification as discussed previously.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-buttons&quot;&gt;o-buttons&lt;/a&gt; adds refresh and cross icon buttons to the default set for Build Service Users; improves spacing between icon and button text; updates pagination buttons with an improved look and new recommendations for the number of pages to show (thanks to Marina Ilieva for the design work here!) If your project uses pagination we recommend reviewing it and adding to your backlog if there’s an opportunity to use the latest o-buttons version to make improvements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-comments&quot;&gt;o-comments&lt;/a&gt; logs a warning if required constructor options are not given; improves the styles for the reported state (credit to Glynn Phillips).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-header&quot;&gt;o-header&lt;/a&gt; makes the height of the sticky nav public with a Sass variable; improves the search close button’s readability (thanks Nick Colley!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-icons&quot;&gt;o-icons&lt;/a&gt; adds a new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;scroll-to&lt;/code&gt; icon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-labels&quot;&gt;o-labels&lt;/a&gt; updates live indicator label animation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-layout&quot;&gt;o-layout&lt;/a&gt; adds a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;listing&lt;/code&gt; element for use with the landing layout, this is useful to list posts on a blog for example.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-message&quot;&gt;o-message&lt;/a&gt;: as discussed above, corrects the padding/margin of messages; adds a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/code&gt; state for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;notice&lt;/code&gt; o-message.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-share&quot;&gt;o-share&lt;/a&gt; adds support for the internal brand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-spacing&quot;&gt;o-spacing&lt;/a&gt; adds &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$o-spacing-names&lt;/code&gt; variable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MINOR: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/polyfill-library&quot;&gt;polyfill-library&lt;/a&gt; adds new features and improvements thanks to open source contributions. Adds a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Intl.Locale&lt;/code&gt; polyfill (thanks &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;longlho&lt;/code&gt;); adds &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextEncoder&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TextDecoder&lt;/code&gt; polyfills (thanks &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lpd-au&lt;/code&gt;); adds a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DOMTokenList.prototype.forEach&lt;/code&gt; polyfill (thanks &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;romainmenke&lt;/code&gt;); rewrites the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Symbol.prototype.description&lt;/code&gt; polyfill to make it work with different &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Symbol&lt;/code&gt; implementations (thanks &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mhassan1&lt;/code&gt;); improves the error message for feature detection tests (thanks &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;romainmenke&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/create-origami-component&quot;&gt;create-origami-component&lt;/a&gt; update &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;getDataAttributes&lt;/code&gt; to only return namespaced data attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/fticons&quot;&gt;fticons&lt;/a&gt; remove the 0x0x1024x1024 viewport requirement from contributing guide, this is no longer required to support raster graphic scaling via the Image Service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-cookie-message&quot;&gt;o-cookie-message&lt;/a&gt; attempts to improve accessibility by implementing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dialogue&lt;/code&gt; role; deprecates the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;standard&lt;/code&gt; theme option (these styles are output by default).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-gallery&quot;&gt;o-gallery&lt;/a&gt; updates the &lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.ft.com/spec/v1/manifest/#supportstatus&quot;&gt;support status&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-gallery&lt;/code&gt; to “dead”, due to its age and low (or no) use. Please let us know if your project relies on &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;o-gallery&lt;/code&gt; still. Note there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami/issues/23&quot;&gt;proposal for a similar carousel component&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-grid&quot;&gt;o-grid&lt;/a&gt; updates the bookmarklet (used to overlay the grid on a website for testing) to use the latest version of o-grid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-normalise&quot;&gt;o-normalise&lt;/a&gt; fixes &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:focus-visible&lt;/code&gt; focus styles (previously broken in Chrome/Edge 68).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-teaser&quot;&gt;o-teaser&lt;/a&gt; registers brand support, to remove the brand support message in the Origami Registry; removes the opinion background from featured “hero image” teasers for desktop-sized viewports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-toggle&quot;&gt;o-toggle&lt;/a&gt; specifies brand support to remove branding warning from the Origami Registry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/o-visual-effects&quot;&gt;o-visual-effects&lt;/a&gt; corrects custom mixin documentation (another thanks for the contribution, Nick Colley!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/origami-build-tools&quot;&gt;origami-build-tools&lt;/a&gt; pa11y runs automated accessibility checks against all brands; fixed an issue that prevented demo JS from initialising reliably.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Financial-Times/stylelint-config-origami-component&quot;&gt;stylelint-config-origami-component&lt;/a&gt;, adds tests to confirm our linting expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Lee Moody</name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html">TL;DR: This issue features Engine Room, Origami v2, and on-site messaging bugs.</summary></entry></feed>